Hello everyone, today I will share with you some of my teaching and practical experience.
My theme is the digitalization of high-precision fabrics.
In our normal work, it is often like this.
For example, your client or your own research has a piece of this kind of fabric.
Then you need to turn it into a digitalized one and apply it to your model.
So that its light, details, and roughness are relatively restored.
And the color must be accurate, including the size.
Then this thing requires certain skills and methods.
So today I will share with you from several aspects.
Mainly I will share from three aspects.
The first is such a work process of digitalized fabrics.
The second is a basic knowledge of our common three-dimensional PBR map.
The third is the scanning processing method of digitalized fabrics.
The first is actually this work process.
Its workflow.
The process is actually divided into such four pieces.
The first is the shooting or scanning of the fabric.
The second is the production of the fabric.
The third is the upload of the fabric.
The fourth is the use of the fabric.
So the actual work reason is divided into such a few pieces.
The first is that you scan and shoot your pattern through your method.
The requirement is that the light is as uniform as possible.
Then the clarity is relatively strong.
The second step is to carry out a reasonable construction.
Because you have to find its circular unit.
Many of our clothing fabrics.
Is a circular pattern.
Or you have to find it.
The third step.
In many cases.
You have to restore your color accurately.
If the color is not accurate.
In fact, this thing.
It doesn't make much sense.
The fourth step.
In addition to the pattern pattern on our surface.
You also have another way of mapping.
Including gloss.
Blur.
Transparency.
These things have to be processed.
The fifth step is to combine your pattern patterns.
With your physical properties.
Then simulate.
Form a material.
The last step is to store it locally.
Or you put it on the close site platform.
To carry out a network disk.
This kind of storage and sharing.
To briefly talk about these six steps.
The second.
Is to introduce the basic knowledge of the PBR pattern.
Then our three-dimensional.
This kind of.
Blur.
It's in a PBR way.
A form of mapping and simulation.
This mapping.
As long as we.
For close.
It's a little bit.
We.
For close.
It includes most of this.
This is the reaction.
Orhhhhhhh.
Call it a lipsie.
Page.
SDFeels Groupx vem.
The second.
It is.
also
Because there is a kind of visual expression.
Normal ERP.
Three?
That is.
If you have a kind of metal texture.
That is the Meta!
MAC2 است egg.
The fourth?
That is, as a whole.
Smoothness.
And we're in the corner, everyone.
Let him be his Ruff Pro hyung.
This is the map.
Ah.
Bootcamp.
The next is, if the lettuce is transparent.
It's called Alpha Map.
And the last one is.
The real texture of the pattern is called the display map.
There are six ways of mapping.
We can take a look at them separately.
The texture of the pattern shows the color and the texture of the surface.
If you show this kind of collective pattern, it is actually a linear mapping.
But this kind of pattern is actually a visual one.
If you want to represent the height of a few centimeters or a few millimeters in the rendering,
it is actually a three-dimensional display map.
The last one is the smoothness.
We call it a reflection map or a rough map.
The other one is the surface of the metal.
It is a map of the texture of the metal.
The last one is a transparent map.
Because there are six parts to some transparency.
We can take a look at how it is applied.
Our clothing fabric is not the same as the picture printing.
For example, our pattern has a fabric pattern.
For example, because you know it,
whether it is true or false, it is known.
So this pattern,
except for the color,
it has the texture of the surface.
It has to be clear to show the category of the clothing.
This is the texture we use in CLO.
The second one is a blue pattern.
We call it a hair line pattern.
It is called a normal pattern.
It is a visual effect formed by a reflection simulation of a computer.
But this visual effect,
after you add this pattern,
for example, this is not the same as the hair line and the hair line.
The degree of detachment is different.
But it is actually a visual detachment.
It is a relatively shallow way of detachment.
The third one,
we can take a look at it.
If it is a real detachment,
for CLO,
it is mainly a visual image.
That is,
some of the black and white pictures we often see.
The white part,
when it is rendered,
it will come out.
The black part remains unchanged.
The whiter it is,
the thicker it is.
So in many cases,
to make a detachment,
many people,
in order to make this detachment,
it is too natural.
So I often make it a little bit of this.
It's blurry.
The surface is blurry.
So you can see that
the degree of detachment is different
between a real detachment
and a real detachment.
The degree of detachment.
The degree of detachment is different.
Everyone remembers
it's whiter and thicker.
That's it.
The next one is a metal decal.
An metal decal is actually a black and white picture.
So the white part
means there is a sense of metal.
The black part means there is none.
Then we can see
the added metal decal
and the no added metal decal.
This effect is different.
So you remember it is a black and white picture.
The white represents the texture of metal.
But it is,
but it is often applied with the reflection in the same way.
It has both metallic and reflective effects,
and it will be much better.
We call this reflection in the cloud.
In fact, if you translate it in English,
it means roughness.
The meaning of roughness is that white means that it is completely rough,
it is not smooth.
The black part is smooth,
it is not rough.
So if you have a metal picture,
you put the roughness picture and the metal picture together,
it is the opposite effect.
The same picture,
one black and one white,
so the metal texture will be stronger.
The next one is the transparency sticker,
it is almost the same,
it is also a black and white picture,
black means transparent,
white means not transparent,
and then this is simpler than if we directly
do a code processing with Photoshop,
because it is too soft on the edges.
If you say that a
black and white picture is transparent,
it means that it is half transparent.
So it's also a black and white picture,
the darker the picture, the more transparent it is,
the whiter the picture, the less transparent it is.
So it's six big stickers.
So let's first have a understanding of this,
and then take a look at how we do it.
This is a way of doing it.
It actually has several devices.
The first one is that,
of course, our material
may be obtained from the Internet,
but the material obtained on the Internet
is often different from what you actually see,
and the actual needs of the Internet are still different.
So if you want to get some fabric from the real world
for digital processing,
then you may have to use a physical method,
and the first common way is
to use a tablet scanner.
It has its advantages and its weaknesses.
The second one is a camera for shooting.
This is a situation that is used more
in our clothing industry.
It is a shooting method
taken with a camera and a light box.
The third one, we have a camera,
and it also has several functions.
But in the case of a normal camera,
it is most likely to be used by the user.
And the fourth one is a scope,
or a facemask.
The fourth one requires a scope.
In this case,
we are not using the
usb scope,
but we can also use a big scope.
This is a small scope.
What is the different between each of them?
It depends.
because it will flatten it, for example, if you find a light-weight material, you scan it and feel that the light-weight material has been mixed in,
that is, because your scanning contact surface is very tight, so it will flatten, so that kind of, we generally use this kind of shooting method will be better,
but for some, for example, very strong hair, for example, some laser, some bright pieces, these can be used to control the parameters in the corollary,
because it has some rendering methods, with hair, bright pieces, laser, this kind of special material parameters to adjust, it may be better,
that is to say, we are not an all-purpose way through the equipment,
then we first talk about some of the features of flat scanning, flat scanning, in general, your fabric is facing down, then flat pressed under this scanning,
our general resolution, it is generally recommended that you are about 600, if it is high, you can 800,
but if it is general, you can 300, but it is generally recommended that 600,
because the storage format of the picture is better to choose PNJ, because in many cases the transparent picture, etc., it needs the PNJ format to remain consistent,
then the frame select a location to scan it, then what are the characteristics of this thing, then we scan it with the Ip sound as an example,
its interface, if you Ip sound, it will have a professional interface, right,
professional interface, then ask you what color, 24 colors, or 48 colors, we generally 24 colors can be,
choose the size, right, and then save the picture, choose a name, save,
but it actually still has some characteristics that need to be noticed, the first is this parameter setting, I made some frames, right,
the second is the resolution of the scan, it is recommended that you are between 600 and 800,
the third has a question, that is, what type of scan to choose, there are two types,
how to have high-end and low-end, there are hundreds of dollars and thousands of dollars, tens of thousands of dollars of scan, what is the difference,
in fact, the most important thing is the difference in sensor components,
sensor components, that is, its core is similar to the lens of the camera, because it is also a sensor lens,
it goes to shoot in the moving process,
then the sensor component has two types of ccd and cis,
the cheaper and faster one is cis,
but the more professional image scan, such as scanning film,
this kind of, it is generally ccd, what is the benefit,
the color restoration is better, the second, it has a depth of field ability, what does it mean,
that is, if your fabric is made into a frame,
leaving this glass surface, there is about a few millimeters of distance,
ccd is able to match the glue, and this cis is not possible, it must be pressed very flat,
but cis also has an advantage, it scans faster,
so it depends on your choice,
for example, I use my usual V850 as an example, it is the ccd scanner,
ccd scanner, you will find that it has two lenses on and off,
the lens surface above, in the traditional case, it is to scan the film,
scan the film, it will have a film frame, the film clip is placed below,
the film clip, the clip is the film, the film and the glass surface above,
have a distance of a few millimeters,
it can match the glue, so this can also remind you,
if you encounter some, for example, a small amount of ccd and other fabrics,
this is not so big,
you can even buy one yourself,
a magnetic clip,
clamped on this scanner,
if you adjust the distance of this focus,
it can also scan clearly,
so as not to let the fabric be pressed flat,
this is my experience,
but the general scanner, only the bottom plane,
in general, it must be attached,
it is not suitable for this kind of more three-dimensional fabric,
in the scanning process,
there will also be two key problems,
the color deviation problem,
in general, the ccd will be a little more accurate,
but the cis will not be very accurate,
the scanner will often be discolored,
especially for our fabrics,
so if you have the conditions,
you can also go and buy Esli's color correction card,
24 color correction card,
it will scan the color correction card first,
and finally generate a color correction file,
stored in the specific location of the computer C disk,
then the scanner,
you can use this color correction file,
the icc color correction curve,
then your scan will be accurate,
according to your color correction,
but in fact, there is another key point,
everyone should also pay attention,
in fact, your screen,
if you use it for a long time,
it will also affect the effect you see at the end,
often it may not be that
the color of your scan is particularly inaccurate,
it is that your screen is discolored,
so if you have the conditions,
you can also use the red spider,
or Esli's color correction chair,
for example,
if you don't use it much,
you can also hire someone to rent it online,
call the color for a period of time,
then your screen display will be better,
otherwise there will be discoloration,
this is the feature of the scanning chair,
I gave you an introduction,
then in my actual use,
there are some small skills,
for example,
the scanning chair at my home,
is the scanning chair of CIS,
that is, the scanning chair for our office,
for example,
if I use my phone to take this picture,
the difference is still quite large,
in fact,
the picture I took with my phone is still very accurate,
then take a picture,
I also recommend that if you can,
it is better to take a picture with an iPhone phone,
because its color reproduction is better than that of a mobile phone in China,
for example,
it may not be so bright,
but the color reproduction is relatively high,
when you are outside in the morning,
but do not direct sunlight,
then the light is more sufficient,
take a picture as a comparison,
then we can use the color matching in Photoshop,
put the picture taken by your phone
and the scan picture
in Photoshop,
then open the image,
adjust the color matching in it,
then the source,
that is, your reference,
choose the picture taken,
then open the picture,
scan this picture,
then it will adjust the color of the picture taken,
your scan picture,
do some adjustment,
then the result will often have a certain effect,
for example,
the picture on the left and the picture on the right,
the left is my scan picture,
the right is the color of the scan picture,
the color of the scan picture is much more accurate,
because the sharpness of your scan picture
is stronger than that of a mobile phone,
so its usability will definitely be higher,
but often the color is not accurate,
and there is no scan card,
your scan is a little bit biased,
then you can try this method,
this method is a little manual,
but it is also effective,
I often use this method,
then the second,
is the large picture scan,
large picture scan,
I found a video,
you can take a look,
this foreign person,
the company uses an A0 size large picture scan,
it was originally to scan the engineering map,
then how to scan the fabric,
he did a process,
the first because the fabric is too soft,
so he found a transparent,
then you use tape,
stick to the starting position,
then he,
because this large picture scan,
like a clip,
then you put your,
with transparent clip,
this position,
pushed into your scan,
he can go in,
if you just put the fabric,
he can't get in,
because he has a glue wheel clip,
then put it in the right place,
then push in,
maybe a few times,
because it is automatically,
to identify this position,
automatically go in,
so sometimes,
to try a few more times,
because I also bought a unit,
a Japanese large picture scan,
also my effect,
can also use,
I'm a little faster,
should,
he has identified,
then he began to operate,
because the starting position,
is very difficult to go,
he may be a test,
then began to go in,
there are some large picture scan,
with a clip,
below a copper plate,
above a layer,
transparent UV,
then change the fabric,
inside,
then go over,
his resolution,
can probably reach,
more than 1200,
in fact,
clear enough,
if you do this,
than,
A3,
A4,
the scanner,
much better,
because it's too wide,
and then,
you have to,
to do,
but I want to tell you,
generally,
this kind of big and small,
are all CIS,
this is the light,
so the color reproduction,
according to,
for example,
the CCD,
still a little weak,
the third kind,
in fact,
is a more professional device,
is the camera scanner,
we call it,
fabric camera scanner,
I gave three examples,
the first is,
the German company,
X-Tex,
it should be,
on the market,
made earlier,
such a device,
a kit,
one of them,
is also a,
this kind of fabric scanner,
its benefits,
there are many benefits,
you can see,
the principle is,
put the camera,
micro unit,
unit,
even industrial camera lens,
combine your light box,
and then,
depends on your ability,
principle,
you can see,
I take one of them as an example,
you see,
there is a light box inside,
top light,
below this also has a light,
side light,
then the camera,
connected,
then,
because I opened the light box,
then the light box,
it can record,
if not,
it can also record,
so you can get a very accurate black and white picture,
then we can see,
what are its advantages,
for example,
there is a color fabric scanning,
then the color fabric,
in fact,
it is different,
then I use some software,
to do a calculation,
to shoot from a different angle,
then record the result,
so it is very accurate,
and you pass,
whether it is our AIGC method,
or through some software,
it is often difficult to be accurate,
because our fabric,
although the color is different,
but its decoloration,
the color is different,
the decoloration is the same,
then it is very troublesome,
especially this multi-colored color,
because,
it can't be determined,
without the depth of the shooting,
so this is the biggest advantage,
of this kind of scanning,
the resolution is very high,
then after the shooting,
the second step,
is to do a circular find,
in fact,
there is this function,
it is easy to open a relatively new version of the color,
there is a fabric called,
color fabric,
such a small tool,
in fact,
the X-Tex software of Vizu company,
can also be used,
and what we often use,
such as Pixplant,
can also get this result,
in fact,
it is still a difficult thing to find a circle,
because we have a lot of fabric,
in addition to this,
the texture is very clear,
the circle is easy to find,
in fact,
there are many,
on the database,
the circle you want to find,
the software still has some algorithms,
for example,
there is an able,
then it has a different algorithm,
it's actually very similar,
but it's not exactly the same,
then I found a circle,
in fact,
you can't find a circle in a single piece,
you have to combine it through an algorithm,
if you are interested,
you can find the official website of Vizu,
It's the same with Pixplan, and it's probably a lot of this kind of material that they use a lot when they do it
You can borrow it
But if you're using a light box, he doesn't have to look for it. As long as he comes in, there's six stickers and then you just have to find a circle and that's it
In other words, the stickers don't have to be taken out directly
But if you use a scanner and other ways, what do you do with the rest of the stickers? You'll have software to calculate
Ah, for example, you have only one texture map to scan and then you have an auto-generate of these graphics
For example, it's not transparent and it's auto-generated, but the accuracy is not necessarily what you want
So you're going to have to look at it and analyze if it meets your requirements
There are not too many parameters and settings for this auto-crawl. It's just a simple one
But for example, let's take Photoshop as an example
Photoshop
The version before 2022
Theunity purple
In this filter you have a 3D filter like this
It has a generated法线图 and a generated print f y
d
You can also picture it in the Forensic version
If it's like me, the colors won't be perfect
We usually can't see it, so it's better to have a version around 2022.
It's more suitable.
It's too old to go any further.
You can pay attention to it.
But if you don't have a transparent map, then you can put it on the sofa.
After entering a picture, use the color range to choose the position you want to be transparent, right?
And then give it a white and black, right?
The transparent one is black.
The non-transparent one is white.
Then give birth to such a map.
It can also be used.
But do some processing of the effect.
This kind of paper, the largest paper, the smallest paper.
You have to make some settings to get a better one.
Otherwise, some places are not clean.
If you put the three-dimensional high film at the end and look at it, it's not very clean.
But the way you take pictures is very good.
So if you use Pixplant, it can also find the loop and do the reflection.
Change the way of these stickers.
If you have the conditions, you can use Pixplant to do this PBR sticker method.
The best way to do this is to use Pixplant.
And then if you're done with these stickers, actually, how do you get your physical properties?
For example, when Kolo was early, he had a set of this kind of semi-hand-made test equipment.
That's how you stretch it.
Test his stretch.
Through this kind of hardness, you bend it to determine the hardness.
And then we use our scale to measure the weight.
And then this kind of thousand-point ruler to measure the thickness.
Of course, he'll cut it into three lines.
And then you put it in and you calculate it.
Create a fabric.
This kind of physical properties.
If you don't have these devices, as long as it's in the cloud, it's in the cloud.
FAB.
He also has a physical property.
How to generate
He's based on the type you chose.
It's a study.
And then the second one is what you're made of.
How much is the third class?
How much is the back?
These two still need to be tested.
He automatically matches a physical property to you based on his big data.
I don't recommend that you make a mess in the parameters.
Because adjustment and actual error are still very large.
His strength is a few comprehensive numbers.
Any data reference is very difficult.
It's very accurate to adjust by hand.
So you don't have to measure it.
You don't have to generate a big number.
That's my suggestion.
Put it together.
It's going to be a perfect fabric.
So I can show you some of the things I've done before.
So I put these six maps in a circle.
Finally, I found a model.
And then I did a light rendering in Blender.
And then his texture and authenticity are higher.
This is in the mouth.
I found a model in there.
Stick it in.
You're going to say some of these transparent maps.
You use what I do with the shooting method.
It works very well.
There won't be a certain position.
There will be this kind of clean problem.
So this is the biggest advantage of the shooting method.
So that's about it for everyone.
Because time is limited.
That's all I'm going to share.